Arch Oboler Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 8. Ranch Files, 1927-1977 (bulk 1950-1970), 8.4 linear feet (20 boxes)
  - Real estate, 1927-1977
    - Bakewell, 1962 July-November (Box 183, Folder 12)
    - Contracts, Mollan ocean land sale, 1955 November-1959 April (Box 183, Folder 13)
    - 4119 St. Clair Ave., 1955 May-1969 February (Box 183, Folder 14)
    - "Perlstein Paradise"
      - Important papers, 1941 May-1963 November, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 183-184, Box 183, Box 184)
      - Miscellaneous, 1955 June-1963 November (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - Ranch real estate
      - 1941 February-1966 May (Box 184, Folder 5)
      - Ranch property "1940-1945," 1941 August-1977 September (Box 184, Folder 6-7)
      - Ranch property "1940-1945," 1927 March-1964 April (Box 184, Folder 8)
    - San Diego, California, 1956 August-1958 June (Box 184, Folder 9)
    - Schwartz affair and easement, 1955 August-1961 January (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Thousand Oaks, California
      - 1957 February-1963 November (Box 185, Folder 2-3)
      - Health suit, 1959 July-September (Box 185, Folder 4)
  - "S" miscellaneous, 1945-1969
    - 1951-1967 (Box 185, Folder 5)
    - Ranch household services, 1954 September-1959 September (Box 185, Folder 6)
    - Sight 'n Sound, 1954 August-November (Box 185, Folder 7)
    - Snyder, Bill, 1952 July-1969 April (Box 185, Folder 8)
    - Stone, Irving, 1945 April (Box 185, Folder 9)
    - Stoumen, Lou, 1952 October-1959 September (Box 185, Folder 10)
  - Scripts, 1954-1969
    - Big Ben, 1954 April-May (Box 185, Folder 11)
    - Fly with a Cherub, correspondence submitted, 1954 December-1969 May (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Letters submitted, fall 1959, 1955 May-1967 November (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - Scripts submitted
      - Own, not returned, 1956 January-1965 February (Box 186, Folder 3)
      - Ashley-Steiner, 1959 February-July (Box 186, Folder 4)
      - Night of the Auk, 1957 November-1958 September (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - Synopsis of "Naked Noah," "Vicious Circle," 1960 April (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - "This Lonely Heart" correspondence, 1960 October (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - "Subway," 1960 May-October (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - "What the Devil" correspondence, 1958 June-November (Box 186, Folder 9)
  - "T" miscellaneous, 1943-1969
    - 1955 November-1968 February (Box 186, Folder 10)
    - 1965 November-1969 (Box 186, Folder 11)
    - Thank-you, congratulatory letters, 1952 December-1968 March (Box 186, Folder 12)
    - Thomson, Norman, 1951 September-1968 December (Box 186, Folder 13)
    - 3D Army, 1963 December (Box 186, Folder 14)
    - 3-D processes
      - Bernier, 1952 October-1963 September (Box 186, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous, 1943 February-1966 January (Box 186, Folder 16)
      - Ramsdell, 1953 March-1954 April (Box 186, Folder 17)
      - Remmlinger, 1957 June-1958 September (Box 186, Folder 18)
    - 1957 "to do" lists, 1957 January-October (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Trips
      - Miscellaneous, 1955 March-1964 November (Box 187, Folder 2)
      - South America, 1954 August-1955 March (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Tru-D, Oboler director contract, 1965 January (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Twonky correspondence, 1952 October-1967 August (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Taxes, 1954-1965 and undated
    - Ideas, 1959 November (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Receipts
      - 1960, 1960 (Box 187, Folder 7)
      - 1961, 1961 March-1962 March (Box 187, Folder 8)
      - 1962, 1961 September-1962 November (Box 187, Folder 9)
    - Employees
      - Correspondence, receipts, etc., 1954, 1954 March-1956 February (Box 187, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, receipts, etc., 1956, 1956 January-1958 November (Box 187, Folder 11)
      - 1960, 1959-1960 (Box 187, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous, 1954 March-1965 May (Box 187, Folder 13)
    - Government investigation, 1956 February-March (Box 187, Folder 14)
    - Klein, 1962, 1954 March-1964 April (Box 187, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 187, Folder 16)
    - Petty cash, 1959, 1958 January-1959 December (Box 187, Folder 17)
    - Typed list of checks, 1956 July-1958 December (Box 187, Folder 18)
  - Television, 1951-1965
    - Jaffee & Wool, 1960, 1961 March-August (Box 187, Folder 19)
    - Advertising companies, 1963 March (Box 187, Folder 20)
    - Four Star, 1961 July-September (Box 187, Folder 21)
    - Alfred Hitchcock, 1962 February (Box 187, Folder 22)
    - Possible employees, 1958 January-1959 (Box 187, Folder 23)
    - Sales possibilities, 1951 August-1965 February (Box 187, Folder 24)
    - Television series, Night of the Awk, 1960 July-August (Box 187, Folder 25)
    - 1957, 1957 August-1960 April (Box 187, Folder 26)
    - Brochure, 1959 February-March (Box 187, Folder 27)
    - Publicity material, 1957 August-1962 January (Box 187, Folder 28)
    - Sales attempts, 1958, 1958 January-1960 March (Box 187, Folder 29)
    - TV sets, 1962 June-July (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Television plays and treatments, circa 1957-1958 and undated
    - "Baby," undated (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - "Bathysphere," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - "Big Shot," masculine, circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 4)
    - "Bright World," undated (Box 188, Folder 5)
    - "Cat Wife," undated (Box 188, Folder 6)
    - "Dog's Eye View," undated (Box 188, Folder 7)
    - "The Dream," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 8)
    - "History of a Mug," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 9)
    - "The Immortal Gentleman," undated (Box 188, Folder 10)
    - "Jackasses and I," undated (Box 188, Folder 11)
    - "Lady Napoleon," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 12)
    - "Love, Love, Love," undated (Box 188, Folder 13-14)
    - "Marriage, 1951," undated (Box 188, Folder 15)
    - "Mirage," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 16)
    - "Mr. Dydee," undated (Box 188, Folder 17)
    - "Mr. Tcitizen," undated (Box 188, Folder 18)
    - "Mr. Vegas," 1958 (Box 188, Folder 19-20)
    - "The Naked Man," undated (Box 188, Folder 21-22)
    - "Night," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 23)
    - "Of Human Bondage," undated (Box 188, Folder 24)
    - "Poltergeist," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 25)
    - "Special to Hollywood," circa 1957 (Box 188, Folder 26)
    - "The Trial of Dr. Watson," undated (Box 188, Folder 27)
    - "Vicious Circle," 1957 August (Box 188, Folder 28)
    - "What the Devil," undated (Box 188, Folder 29)
    - "Wonderful World," undated (Box 188, Folder 30-31)
  - "U" miscellaneous, 1953-1968
    - 1953 October-1968 November (Box 189, Folder 1)
    - United Artists, 1953 July-1954 May (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Unions, 1951-1969
    - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists (AFTRA), 1963-1968 (Box 189, Folder 3)
    - Authors League of America, 1955 (Box 189, Folder 4)
    - Dramatists Guild, 1956 July-1966 June (Box 189, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952 June-1955 November (Box 189, Folder 6)
    - Screen Directors Guild, 1951 October-1969 March (Box 189, Folder 7)
    - Writers Guild, 1954 March-1969 May (Box 189, Folder 8-9)
  - "V" miscellaneous, 1953-1955
    - Variety, 1953 December-1955 November (Box 189, Folder 10)
  - "Y" miscellaneous, 1965 January-April (Box 189, Folder 11)
  - "W-Y-Z" miscellaneous, 1953-1967
    - 1953-1967 (Box 189, Folder 12)
    - Ward, Kathleen, 1959 September-1960 December (Box 189, Folder 13)
- Series 9. Scripts, 1933-1993 and undated, 70 linear feet (168 boxes)
  The largest series in the Oboler papers, the Scripts series showcases Oboler’s work at his creative best and at the height of his popularity, when he wrote and directed numerous works for radio shows such as Lights Out, Arch Oboler’s Plays, Everyman's Theater, To the President, Plays for Americans, and Free World Theatre.
  Most scripts are retained in the collection in multiple copies of various versions, including original, corrected, revised, edited, and as broadcast. Oboler apparently maintained at least two separate collections of his scripts, the “Fire” file (possibly at his residence) and the “Town” file (possibly at his long-time office at 4119 St. Clair Avenue, Studio City, California). All versions of scripts from the Fire and Town files and from other locations are grouped together and arranged alphabetically by title.
  The Scripts series contains virtually all of Oboler’s pre-war work in the horror, humor, romance, and drama genres, as well as early anti-war radio plays and scripts of his wartime broadcasts supporting American and Allied war efforts against global totalitarianism. Oboler’s trademark stream-of-conscious narration is evident in many of the scripts, as is his penchant for reworking, re-recording, and re-titling story lines. Ever seeking new opportunities, Oboler proposed a number of new radio series during his career, and the Scripts series contains summaries of these proposals, which he attempted, in many cases without success, to sell to radio networks.
  - Indexes and summaries, 1934-1958 and undated
    - Arch Oboler's Plays series, 1939-1940, 1954 (Box 190, Folder 1)
    - Arch Oboler's Plays series, town file, 1939-1940 (Box 190, Folder 2)
    - Everyman's Theater series
      - Country file, 1940-1941 (Box 190, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1940-1941 (Box 190, Folder 4)
    - Everything for the Boys series, undated (Box 190, Folder 5)
    - Free World Theatre series, 1943 (Box 190, Folder 6)
    - Grand Hotel series, 1934-1940 (Box 190, Folder 7)
    - Mark Twain series, 1944 (Box 190, Folder 8)
    - Mark Twain series, town file, 1944 (Box 190, Folder 9)
    - NBC and Mutual radio series promotional posters, 1945, undated (Box OS 1, Folder 8)
    - Plays for Americans series, 1942 (Box 190, Folder 10)
    - Script indexes, 1957-1958, undated (Box 190, Folder 11)
    - To the President series, 1942 (Box 190, Folder 12)
    - Your Hollywood Parade series, 1937-1938 (Box 190, Folder 13)
    - Card index of Oboler's radio series and episodes, undated (Box 363)
      Card box containing two indexes, each arranged alphabetically by program and episode title.
  - Free World Theatre, 1943
    A series of radio plays that were produced, directed, and in part written by Arch Oboler and broadcast February 21-June 27, 1943, on the NBC Blue Network.
    As part of his support of American involvement in World War II, Oboler requested statements intended for the American people from various world leaders and thinkers, such as Franklin D. Roosevelt, Winston Churchill, Josef Stalin, Thomas Mann, and Aldous Huxley. These were then dramatized for radio by Oboler and others. Stars of the broadcasts included Orson Welles, Fred MacMurrary, Judy Garland, Joseph Cotten, James Cagney, Lena Horne, Jackie Cooper, and others. The series was funded by the U.S. Office of War Information.
    Published in: Arch Oboler and Stephen Longstreet, editors. Free World Theatre: Nineteen New Radio Plays, with an introduction by Thomas Mann and a preface by Arch Oboler. New York: Random House, 1944.
    - "The People March," broadcast 1943 February 21, Written by Arch Oboler (Box 190, Folder 14)
    - "Tomorrow," broadcast 1943 February 28, Written by Budd Schulberg and Jerome Lawrence (Box 190, Folder 15)
    - "Your Day Is Coming," broadcast 1943 March 7, Written by Allan Scott (Box 190, Folder 16)
    - "Rip von Dinkel of Nuremberg" and "I Have No Prayer," broadcast 1943 March 14 (Box 190, Folder 17)
    - "White House Kitchen," broadcast 1943 March 21, Written by B.C. Schoenfeld (Box 190, Folder 18)
    - "Music for Freedom," broadcast 1943 March 28, Written by Don Quinn, Ira Greshwin, Jay Gorney, Henry Myers, and Edward Eliscu (Box 190, Folder 19)
    - "The Fountain of Dancing Children," broadcast 1943 April 4, Written by Fanya F. Lawrence (Box 191, Folder 1-2)
    - "Night Flight," broadcast 1943 April 11, Written by Arch Oboler (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - "Fiesta," broadcast 1943 April 18, Written by Richard Collins and Everett Tomlinson (Box 191, Folder 4-5)
    - "S.S. Middletown," broadcast 1943 April 25, Written by Hector Chevigny, Anne Anthony, and Jerome Lawrence (Box 191, Folder 6-7)
    - "China to America," broadcast 1943 May 2, Written by Pearl Buck (Box 191, Folder 8-9)
    - "Last Will and Testament of Tom Smith," broadcast 1943 May 9, Written by Stephen Longstreet (Box 191, Folder 10-11)
    - "My Mothers Never Weep," broadcast 1943 May 16, Written by William Kozlenko (Box 191, Folder 12-13)
    - "Something about Joe," broadcast 1943 May 23, Written by Milton Merlin and Clarence Muse (Box 192, Folder 1-2)
    - "Man with a Beard," broadcast 1943 May 30, Written by Talbot Jennings (Box 192, Folder 3-4)
    - "General Armchair," broadcast 1943 June 6, Written by Samuel Raphaelson (Box 192, Folder 5-6)
    - "The Second Battle of Warsaw," broadcast 1943 June 13, Written by Irving Ravetch (Box 192, Folder 7-8)
    - "In Memory of a Hero," broadcast 1943 June 20, Written by Howard Estabrook (Box 192, Folder 9-10)
    - "V-Day," broadcast 1943 June 27, Written by Arch Oboler (Box 192, Folder 11-12)
  - Radio, 1933-1981 and undated
    - "About My Mother"
      - Fire file, 1942 November (Box 193, Folder 1)
      - Town file, 1942 November (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - "Acrophobia"
      - Fire file, 1937 February (Box 193, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1937 February (Box 193, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous file, undated (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - "Across the Gap (Neanderthal Man)"
      - Fire file, 1942 November (Box 193, Folder 6-7)
      - Town file, 1942 November (Box 193, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous file, undated (Box 193, Folder 9)
    - "Adam's Weak Rib"
      - Fire file, 1937 September (Box 194, Folder 1)
      - Town file, 1937 September (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - "Adolph and Mrs. Runyon"
      - Fire file, 1942 February-March, June (Box 194, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1942 June (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - "Adults Only"
      - Fire file, 1937 October, December, 1941 January (Box 194, Folder 5)
      - Town file, 1937 December, 1941 January (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - "Adventure," 1946 April (Box 194, Folder 7)
      Weekly series.
    - "Adventure in Tomorrow," 1950-1951 (Box 194, Folder 8)
      Radio series proposal.
    - "Adventure Postponed"
      See also "Finale"
      - Fire file, 1937 December, 1939 September (Box 194, Folder 9-10)
      - Town file, 1939 September (Box 194, Folder 11-12)
    - "The Adventures of Tom Sawyer"
      - Fire file, 1944 January (Box 195, Folder 1)
      - Town file, 1944 January (Box 195, Folder 2)
    - African Adventure, circa 1950 (Box 195, Folder 3)
    - "African Story"
      - Fire file, 1949 July, 1964 January (Box 195, Folder 4-5)
      - Town file, 1949 July, 1964 January (Box 195, Folder 6-8)
      - "African Adventure, Man-Eaters of Tsavo," 1949 July (Box 195, Folder 9-10)
      - "A Day with the Hartleys," undated (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - "Afternoon Adventure"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 196, Folder 2)
      - Town file, undated (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - "Afternoon of a Faun"
      - Fire file, 1936 December (Box 196, Folder 4)
      - Town file, 1936 December (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - "Alter Ego"
      - Fire file, 1936 November, 1939 July (Box 196, Folder 6)
      - Town file, 1936 November, 1939 July, 1945 February (Box 196, Folder 7)
      - Radio Hall of Fame fire file, 1945 April (Box 196, Folder 8)
      - Radio Hall of Fame town file, 1945 April (Box 196, Folder 9)
    - "American and a Man"
      - Fire file, circa 1944 February (Box 196, Folder 10)
      - Town file, circa 1944 February (Box 196, Folder 11)
    - "An American Is Born"
      - Fire file (Box 196-197)
        - 1940 November, 1942 January, 1943 June, (1 folder) (Box 196)
        - 1940 November, 1942 January, 1943 June, (1 folder) (Box 197)
      - Town file, 1940 November, 1942 January, 1943 June (Box 197, Folder 2-3)
    - "The Amorous Ghost," 1945 May (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - "And Adam Begot (Homo Primus)"
      - Fire file, 1937 March, 1939 September, 1940 October (Box 197, Folder 5-6)
      - Town file, 1937 March, 1939 September, 1940 October (Box 197, Folder 7-8)
    - "Anna"
      - Fire file, 1941 July, October (Box 197, Folder 9)
      - Town file, 1941 July, October (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - "Anne Williams"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 198, Folder 2)
      - Town file, undated (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - "Anniversary"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 198, Folder 4)
      - Town file, undated (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - "Annual Honeymoon"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 198, Folder 6)
      - Town file, undated (Box 198, Folder 7)
    - "Another Life"
      - Fire file, 1936 July (Box 198, Folder 8)
      - Town file, 1936 July (Box 198, Folder 9)
    - "Another World" See "Alter Ego" (Box 198, Folder 10)
    - "The Answer"
      - Fire file, 1943 September (Box 198, Folder 11)
      - Town file, 1943 September (Box 198, Folder 12)
    - "Applause"
      - Fire file, circa 1943 December (Box 198, Folder 13)
      - Town file, circa 1943 December (Box 198, Folder 14)
    - "Arch Oboler's Africa," undated (Box 198, Folder 15)
    - "Arch Oboler's African Adventures"
      - NBC Monitor announcements, circa 1959 (Box 198, Folder 16)
      - NBC Monitor correspondence, 1959 (Box 198, Folder 17)
      - NBC Monitor tape log, circa 1950 (Box 198, Folder 18)
      - Sales letters, circa 1950-1960 (Box 198, Folder 19)
    - "The Archer"
      - Fire file, 1937 October, 1943 April (Box 198, Folder 20)
      - Town file, 1937 October, 1943 April (Box 199, Folder 1-2)
    - "Arctic Adventure"
      - Fire file, 1937 February (Box 199, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1937 February (Box 199, Folder 4)
    - "The Author and the Thing"
      - Fire file, 1936 September, 1943 September (Box 199, Folder 5-6)
      - Town file, 1936 September, 1943 September (Box 199, Folder 7)
    - "Autumn Flower"
      - Fire file, 1939 October (Box 199, Folder 8)
      - Town file, 1939 October (Box 199, Folder 9)
    - "Avenue A," fire file, circa 1934 (Box 199, Folder 10)
    - "Awful Oracle" See later title, "Lady Napoleon" (Box 199, Folder 11)
    - "Baby"
      - Fire file, 1939-1942, (1 folder) (Box 199-200, Box 199, Box 200)
      - Town file, 1939-1941 (Box 200, Folder 2)
    - "Baby Talk"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 200, Folder 3)
      - Town file, undated (Box 200, Folder 4)
    - "Back to the Indians"
      - Fire file, 1940 January (Box 200, Folder 5)
      - Town file, 1940 January (Box 200, Folder 6)
    - "Back Where You Came From"
      - Fire file, 1942 June (Box 200, Folder 7)
      - Town file, 1942 June (Box 200, Folder 8)
    - "The Ball"
      - Fire file, 1943 March (Box 200, Folder 9)
      - Town file, 1938 March, 1943 March (Box 200, Folder 10)
    - "Baroness Munchausen"
      - Fire file, 1934 April (Box 201, Folder 1)
      - Town file, 1934 April (Box 201, Folder 2)
    - "Bathysphere"
      - Fire file, 1939 November, 1943 June, 1964 January (Box 201, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1939 November, 1943 June, 1964 January (Box 201, Folder 4-6)
    - "Beast of the Shamo"
      - Fire file, 1937 January (Box 201, Folder 7)
      - Town file, 1937 January (Box 201, Folder 8)
    - "Beautiful Lady"
      - Fire file, circa 1936, 1937 November (Box 202, Folder 1)
      - Town file, circa 1936, 1937 November (Box 202, Folder 2)
    - "Bedtime Story: Adults Only," 1946 February (Box 202, Folder 3-4)
    - "Berkeley Square"
      - Fire file, 1944 February (Box 202, Folder 5)
      - Town file, 1944 February (Box 202, Folder 6)
    - "Bewitched," town file, undated (Box 202, Folder 7)
    - "Big Ben"
      - NANA tape log, 1964 January 14 (Box 202, Folder 8)
      - Radio play, 1949 May (Box 202, Folder 9)
    - "Big Shot"
      - Feminine: Mutual, as broadcast, 1945 July 2 (Box 202, Folder 10)
      - Feminine: Fire file, 1945 July (Box 202, Folder 11)
      - Feminine: Town file, 1945 July (Box 202, Folder 12)
      - Masculine: Fire file, 1945 September (Box 203, Folder 1-2)
      - Fire file, 1937 January (Box 203, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1937 January (Box 203, Folder 4)
    - "Big Town"
      - Fire file, circa 1937 November (Box 203, Folder 5)
      - Town file, circa 1937 November (Box 203, Folder 6)
    - "Birds of a Feather"
      - Fire file, 1937 August (Box 203, Folder 7)
      - Town file, 1937 August (Box 203, Folder 8)
    - "Black Birthday," miscellaneous file, undated (Box 203, Folder 9)
    - "Black Buddha"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 203, Folder 10)
      - Town file, undated (Box 203, Folder 11)
    - "Black Pirate"
      - Fire file, 1936 September (Box 203, Folder 12)
      - Town file, 1936 September (Box 203, Folder 13)
    - "Black Zombie"
      - Fire file, 1937 August, 1937 October (Box 203, Folder 14)
      - Town file, 1937 August, 1937 October (Box 203, Folder 15)
    - "Blackouts," fire and town files, circa 1943 (Box 203, Folder 16)
    - "Blithe Spirit"
      - Fire file, 1944 May (Box 203, Folder 17)
      - Town file, 1944 May (Box 204, Folder 1)
    - "Blonde Help Wanted"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 204, Folder 2)
      - Town file, undated (Box 204, Folder 3)
    - "Blood Story"
      - Fire file, 1942 April, June (Box 204, Folder 4)
      - Town file, 1942 April (Box 204, Folder 5)
    - "Bomber to Tokyo"
      - Fire file, 1942 May (Box 204, Folder 6)
      - Town file, 1942 May (Box 204, Folder 7)
    - "Bon Voyage"
      - Fire file, 1938 June, 1942 November (Box 204, Folder 8)
      - Town file, 1938 June, 1942 November (Box 204, Folder 9)
    - "The Bones of Sam Lee (The Thirteenth Corpse)"
      - Fire file, 1937 March, 1943 January (Box 204, Folder 10)
      - Town file, 1937 March, 1943 January (Box 204, Folder 11)
    - "Book of Ruth," fire and town files, undated (Box 204, Folder 12)
    - "Box-Car," fire and town files, undated (Box 204, Folder 13)
    - "Boy of Mine"
      - Fire file, circa 1935 (Box 204, Folder 14)
      - Town file, circa 1935 (Box 204, Folder 15)
    - "Boy Trouble"
      - Fire file, 1937 May (Box 205, Folder 1)
      - Town file, 1937 May (Box 205, Folder 2)
    - "Boy Wanted"
      - Fire file, 1934 October (Box 205, Folder 3)
      - Town file, 1934 October (Box 205, Folder 4)
    - "Brain Storm"
      - Fire file, 1941 August (Box 205, Folder 5)
      - Town file, 1941 August (Box 205, Folder 6)
    - "Brain Wave (Brain King)"
      - Fire file, 1937 July (Box 205, Folder 7)
      - Town file, 1937 July (Box 205, Folder 8)
    - "The Brave One"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 205, Folder 9)
      - Town file, undated (Box 205, Folder 10)
    - "Bread on the Waters," fire and town files, undated (Box 205, Folder 11)
    - "Breakfast in the Country," town file, undated (Box 205, Folder 12)
    - "Bright Weapon"
      - circa 1943-1944, circa 1947, (1 folder) (Box 205-206, Box 205, Box 206)
      - Town file, circa 1943-circa 1944, circa 1947 (Box 206, Folder 2-5)
    - "Bright World," fire file, 1938 February, 1941 January, 1941 July (Box 206, Folder 6)
    - "Bronx Hero," fire and town files, undated (Box 206, Folder 7)
    - "Brother Jim"
      - Fire file, 1937 June (Box 206, Folder 8)
      - Town file, 1937 June (Box 206, Folder 9)
    - "Bull by the Horns"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 206, Folder 10)
      - Town file, undated (Box 206, Folder 11)
    - "Bull's-Eye"
      - Fire file, undated (Box 207, Folder 1)
      - Town file, undated (Box 207, Folder 2)
    - "Bundles for Britain," fire and town files, undated (Box 207, Folder 3)
    - "Burial Services"
      Oboler's first Lights Out script.
      - Fire file, 1936 June (Box 207, Folder 4)
      - Town file, 1936 June (Box 207, Folder 5)
    - "The Busy Bachelors"
      - Fire file, 1936 September (Box 207, Folder 6)
      - Town file, 1936 September, 1949 December (Box 207, Folder 7)
    - "Cat Wife", One alternate title: "Young Ideas."
      A popular episode of Lights Out in which a man's wife becomes a cat the size of a human.